我们在零重力之中起舞
We can dance in zero G
飞速旅行到遥远的星际
Traveling fast far from galaxy
需要特殊的快递吗
Need a special delivery
只需叫上Malo Korrigan
Just call Malo Korrigan
但不是免费的
But it's not free
Malo Korrigan
没人能打倒你
Nobody will bring you down
Malo Korrigan
生活在宇宙中
live in space
翻译、时间轴、后期：Bolshevik0
#4        大鼠
Roberta, we are in the middle of some strange ionic phenomena.
Roberta 我们在某种奇怪的离子物质中
Never seen anything like it.
从没见过这种东西
It's glowing all around me.
它就在我周围发光
Oh, where exactly are you?
哦 那你具体在哪
I'm heading towards CO Lovas.
我正前往CO Lovas
Hmm, it's on the NKX5
恩 它在NKX5
and must be the soul of a brief alizarin supernova.
它是一个寿命短暂的超红巨星的残骸
Well, anyway, it looks pretty festive around here.
好吧 不管怎样 这儿看起来挺有节日气氛
Look they're so something's just like there's 20 years ago.
它们就像20年前那样
You're glowing because of the static electricity
由于静电的作用导致你们在发光.
Oh, it's all right.
哦 这没关系
Don't touch anything or anyone until you're out of the area.
在离开这片区域前不要触摸任何东西或者任何人
Oh I guess Roberta was right.
哦 我猜Roberta是对的
Kiwk, Kiwk?
Kiwk Kiwk
Kiwk Kiwk, where are you?
Kiwk Kiwk 你在哪
Jonas, I need a damage report.
Jonas 我需要损失报告
What's our situation?
我们现在怎样
Jonas?
Jonas
Hello.
有人吗
Jonas?
Jonas
Oh, Jonas, where are you?
哦 Jonas 你在哪
Holy ark!
天哪
I'm right here.
我就在这儿
Checking out the damage.
检查故障
So?
有什么问题吗
Nothing serious.
没什么大不了的
But the main problem is that
但主要问题是
the ship is charged with 20 million volts of static electricity
飞船被充上了2千万伏的静电荷
and they're gonna discharge as soon as we touch the ground
而我们接触地面时就会放电
and then kaboom.
接着爆炸
Is that all?
这有问题吗
Everything within a kilometer, the Starduke, we'll burn to a crisp.
一公里之内的所有东西包括星爵号都会被炸成碎片
Okay, we will land on the nearest uninhabited asteroid.
好吧 我们就近降落在无人小行星上吧
In the meantime, Cyana,
与此同时 Cyana
could you bring our passengers a little something to eat
你能给我们的乘客吃点什么吗
and make sure they're comfortable?
并确保他们处在舒适的环境中
Oh, whatever you say.
哦 随你怎么说
Oh...
呃
I can't believe that some people call this lunch.
我真不敢相信有些人把这个当饭吃
Come and get it.
过来吃吧
The nearest asteroid,
最近的小行星
that the SDX7,
叫SDX7
the coordinates are 28-32,
坐标是28-32
I'll find out more and then I'll get back to you.
等我查阅更多信息之后再跟你联系
Okay.
好的
Thanks Roberta.
谢谢你 Roberta
So, are our passengers good?
我们的乘客还好吗
Why in the world would you have accepted to take those x2 creatures?
你为啥能接受这些乘客
Because they're paying for it.
因为他们付了钱
You know, princess, the Daisukis are quite famous on CO Lovas.
你知道的 公主 大鼠种族在CO Lovas可是相当受欢迎
Famous for what?
因什么而受欢迎啊
For scaring little children?
吓唬小朋友吗
Listen, Cyana, all extraterrestrials have their own characteristics.
Cyana 所有外星种族都有着他们独特的特征
There it is, SDX7.
这就是SDX7
Strange-looking rock.
是个很奇怪的石头
Looks like overcooked gummy.
看起来像烤糊了的胶
All right now. Hang on site.
现在好了 大家扶稳了
This is gonna be rough.
这会有点颠簸
Holy comics!
天哪
We're gonna flip over.
我们要翻滚一下
Wasn't so bad.
还好
Piece of cake, actually.
实际上还挺简单
Jonas, how's my baby doing.
Jonas 飞船怎么样
Jonas.
Jonas
All right I'm coming. I'm coming.
好了 我来了
Well, electricity discharged.
好的 电荷都释放掉了
You'll buy repairs to the cockpit
你得为驾驶舱买备件了
and we'll have enough energy to get out of here.
接着我们就有足够的动力离开这里
But it'll still be a good idea to check outside.
当然 最好还是出去检查一下
I'll take care of it.
我来去吧
What a strange place.
这地方真奇怪
How'd you look out there?
你在外面检查得怎么样
Not great but we should be able to take off.
不是很好 但我们应该可以起飞
I'm coming in.
我进来了
I'm... I'm almost done.
我很快就好了
Kiwk Kiwk?
Kiwk Kiwk
Leave Kiwk Kiwk alone.
放开Kiwk Kiwk
Kiwk Kiwk, are you alright?
Kiwk Kiwk 你还好吗
You better stay with Jonas.
你最好和Jonas呆一块
Get back to your room now.
现在赶快回到你们的舱室去
Recess is over.
休息已经结束了
Get away from me.
放开我
Everything alright?
一切都还好吗
Oh, our passengers were exploring.
哦 我们的乘客之前在四处闲逛
I got them back in though.
不过我让他们都回去了
They really give me the creeps.
他们真的让我脊背发冷
I wonder what they must think of us.
我正好奇他们该怎么看待我们的
I'd rather not talk about it if you don't mind.
如果你不介意 我并不想提起此事
Can we go?
我们能出发了吗
Right away, ma'am.
没问题 女士
Shut it down.
关掉它
Strange. There wasn't anything here a minute ago.
奇怪 一分钟前这儿并没有东西
It's like these rocks climbed up the side of a Starduke.
看起来这些岩石爬到了星爵号的一边
It looks like it stuck in a black ice.
看起来像是卡在了黑色的冰块中
You used to have a boat on earth.
在地球的时候你曾开着水里的船
How would they get out of it?
就会想着怎么把这些东西搞下来
Some would wait for it to melt.
有些人会一直等着它们融化
But I prefer to help the process along a little.
但是我希望这个过程能快一点
Malo, this is important.
Malo 这很重要
I just find out the SDX7 is a Class S asteroid.
我刚刚发现SDX7是一个等级S的小行星
You need a special authorization to land.
你着陆的时候需要特别的许可
Do not go near it under any circumstances.
在任何情况下都不要靠近它
The consequences could be fatal.
后果可能致命
Kiwk Kiwk?
Kiwk Kiwk
Come here.
过来
Hold on tight.
抓稳了
You better hang out to your head.
你最好抓住你的头
Well, that was a waste to explosives.
看起来浪费了炸药
注:
globular cluster是恒星团的意思，这里大概就是感叹词
Great globular clusters.
天哪
I'm not gonna let those slugs eat away the ship.
我不会让那些蛞蝓吃掉我的飞船
I see that old thing is still as good as ever?
这老东西依然和之前一样好吗
I'm telling you I just fixed it.
我跟你说我刚修复了它
If the entire asteroid was...
如果这整个小行星都是
Holy comics.
天哪
I don't think that slug is very happy.
我不认为这个蛞蝓心情很好
Cyana!
Cyana
Our friend.
我们的朋友
But I understand you.
我怎么听懂了你说的话
We have entered your mind and now we are able to communicate.
我们进到了你的脑海中 这样就能沟通了
And we have also entered the mind of the asteroid.
而且我们也进入到了小行星的脑海中
It is alive.
它是活着的
That is why it is defending himself.
这就是为什么他在保卫自己
It's alive?
它活着吗
It suffers from our friends.
我们的朋友正在损害它
And from any even greater evil.
甚至一些更强大的恶魔也在摧残它
But what can we do?
那我们能做什么
Cure it.
治好它
Well, looks like we have no choice
好吧 看起来我们只能
but to shoot our way out.
杀出一条血路
I'll show them what kind of proton's a meal.
我会告诉他们质子枪如何烧制出一顿饭
Malo, Jonas, where are you?
Malo Jonas 你们在哪
We're in a pile of trouble.
我们身处一堆麻烦当中
What's the situation on the ship?
船上的情况如何
What can you see from where you are?
你们那儿能看到什么
Nothing but a giant maggots.
除了大虫子以外没看到啥
There's some sort of metal structure.
那边好像有个金属建筑
Looks like a probe.
看起来像是个探测器
Yes that's it.
就是那玩意儿
Do you have any Z-17 left?
你们还有Z-17炸药吗
Oh yeah.
有啊
And I'm gonna feed into the slugs for dinner
我正准备当作晚餐喂给那些蛞蝓
if they keep this up with a cop going to the chef.
如果他们还继续作乱 那警察也得把他们拿来做饭
Listen to me.
听我说
Hang on to it.
坚持住
But we're gonna need it later.
我们过会才需要它
First step. Get closer to the probe.
第一步 靠近探测器
She lost her mind?
她疯了吗
Oh, I figured out what's happening here.
哦 我大概知道这儿发生了什么
This is just an asteroid.
这只是个小行星
This rock's alive.
这块石头是活着的
Yeah, alright.
好吧没错
So you lost your mind too.
你也疯了
Ok, old tracer, just say when.
老伙计 就等你了
They're fools and surrounding my fools.
这些蠢家伙围着我的蠢同伴
It's a mining bro left by the Consortium.
这是个财团留下的挖矿机器人
Cyana, we are in the position.
Cyana 我们就位了
How did you know there was a program?
你怎么知道这件事的
The asteroid told the rats.
小行星把这件事跟大鼠说了
And they told me.
然后大鼠又转告给我
You won that bet again.
你又赌赢了
What can we say, Jonas.
这事儿挺绝的 Jonas
The asteroid is a lonely king.
这个小行星是个孤独的国王
The probe is making him suffer.
探测器正在摧残着小行星
Exactly.
没错
And those Gigantic robot is just a failure.
而这个巨大的机器人不过是个失败品
And then, we gonna keep them ahead.
不过我们会解决这个问题
Jonas, you set these explosives.
Jonas 你来放置炸弹
I take care of those slugs.
我来处置这些蛞蝓
To attract inner guards, you have to become a virus.
为了吸引这些免疫细胞 你需要变成病毒
He's totally out of his mind.
他完全疯掉了
Hey, fellas! It's nothing to see over there.
嘿 伙计们 那儿没啥好注意的
Ah!
啊
Holy supernovas! What an explosion!
真是巨大的爆炸
The asteroid is cured.
小行星被治愈了
And Malo?
而Malo呢
Well there...
好吧
There were slugs all around the probe and...
探测器周围有些蛞蝓
Malo he...
Malo他
And Malo he... What?
咋了
He just went for a walk and stretch his legs out a little bit.
他只是出去散了回步
So, what's happened to the slugs?
那这些蛞蝓呢
Well I told them I was a friend of yours
我说了我是你们的朋友
and then scared them off.
就把它们吓跑了
What's the deal with you?
你这边怎么样
Everything's been taken care of.
所有东西都处理得很好
I think we can leave the asteroid now, captain.
船长 我觉得我们可以离开小行星了
What?
什么
So I'm not let to say hello to my friend now?
难道我不能和我的朋友打招呼了吗
Of course you're.
你当然可以
That's normal.
这很正常
Because she's loved shaking with their little tentacles.
因为她很喜欢和大鼠的小手握在一起
Malo, Cyana, finally you're back.
Malo Cyana 你们终于回来了
Did you get my message?
你们收到了我的消息吗
SDX7 is a Class S asteroid, you mustn't land on it.
SDX7是一个S等级的小行星 你不可以降落在上面
Thanks, Roberta. But you're a little late.
谢谢你 Roberta 不过你说的有点晚
What?
怎么了
You landed on it?
你在上面降落了吗
Well, how was it?
那地方究竟如何
Uh, routine.
呃 例行公事而已
我们在零重力之中起舞
We can dance in zero G
飞速旅行到遥远的星际
Traveling fast far from galaxy
Malo Korrigan
没人能打倒你
Nobody will bring you down
Malo Korrigan
生活在宇宙中
live in space